Michelle Polon

Full-Stack Software Developer http://michellepolan.com

(717) 318-6104

gemini6879@gmail.com
https://github.com/TinyPilot06
https://linkedin.com/in/michelle-polan

OBJECTIVE

Motivated and dependable professional transitioning from a successful career in the gaming industry to software development. With a foundational knowledge in web & mobile development and a passion for technology and innovation, I am eager to apply my skills and grow professionally under expert guidance. I aim to contribute effectively to my future team and to continually strive to become an expert in the field.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages
 JavaScript/TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SASS
- Frameworks & Technologies
 React/React Native, Node.js, Django, MongoDB, MUI, AWS Lambda, Docker
- Databases
 PostgreSQL, DynamoDB
- Tools
 Git, Docker

PROJECTS

Music Library Management WebApp

React, TypeScript, Material UI, Node.js, Cognito, Lambda, DynamoDB, S3

Developed a full-featured music library management application focusing on serverless architecture with AWS Lambda functions and DynamoDB for data management. Front end built in React/TypeScript using Material UI v5.

Portfolio Website - <u>MichellePolan.com</u> React, TypeScript, Material UI v5, ThreeJS

Built a single-page application (SPA) portfolio website to promote myself, my work experience, education, and resume.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Developer November 2023 - Present

Remote

- <u>Frontend Development</u> Design and build user interfaces with React and Typescript, incorporating Material UI v5 for responsive, intuitive, user-friendly experiences.
- <u>Backend Development</u> Utilize serverless AWS Lambda functions to ensure scalability, cost effectiveness, and seamless deployment. Configure and use AWS S3 for scalable secure storage. Design and utilize DynamoDB No-SQL database architecture for high-performance data retrieval.
- <u>Authentication and Security</u> Integrate AWS Cognito for secure user authentication and authorization, ensuring data privacy and protected access to backend APIs.
- <u>Stakeholder Communication</u> Maintain consistent communication and feedback sessions with clients and stakeholders to ensure smooth evolution of software designs, functionality, and delivery expectations.

Blackjack Dealer, Pit Supervisor May 2012 - Present

Seminole HardRock Hotel and Casino 5223 Orient Road, Tampa, FL 33610

- Excelled in a high-pressure environment, managing games for high-stake clients and high rollers.
- Oversee a section of dealers, keeping an eagle-eye on money exchanges, card-counters, and unruly guests.
- Utilized excellent communication and humor to maintain a positive atmosphere and diffuse tensions.
- Demonstrated a strong work ethic and commitment to community service through volunteering in company-led initiatives.

Office Manager October 2011 - May 2012 TM Realty, LLC. 3275 Arbor Pointe Cir, Tampa, FL 33617

- Managed rent and HOA dues collection and delinquency.
- Organized agendas for homeowner board meetings.
- Managed maintenance staff and addressed issues for owners and tenants.

Waitress June 2001 - December 2011 The Cheesecake Factory Restaurants 2223 N Westshore Blvd., Tampa, FL 33607

• Excelled in customer service in the high-pressure, fast-paced environment of a wildly popular premium restaurant brand.

- Demonstrably strong work ethic and company loyalty.
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills honed in high-pressure service environments.
- Adaptability and eagerness to learn and apply new technologies.

EDUCATION, CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

- Web Development Fundamentals, nuCamp
- Backend, SQL, and DevOps with Python, nuCamp
- Front End and Mobile Development, nuCamp

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

- Continuously engaging in self-directed learning through online resources, focusing on web design, user experience, and modern web technologies like AWS, React, and Three.js.
- When I'm not coding, I like to build with Lego, play video games, root for the Ravens, and work out at the gym.